<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GrantSeltzer</title>
    <link>https://grantseltzer.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on GrantSeltzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 03:32:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grantseltzer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding cgroups</title>
      <link>https://grantseltzer.github.io/blog/understanding-cgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 03:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantseltzer.github.io/blog/understanding-cgroups/</guid>
      <description>This post will introduce you to cgroups. The goal is to give a comprehensive enough explanation of cgroups and subsystems to broadly understand what they accomplish and how. The major focus will be on the CPU cgroup. The second section and third section will explore using cgroups from the command line. 
Control groups (or cgroups) are a feature of the Linux kernel by which groups of processes can be monitored and have their resources limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting Go Binaries</title>
      <link>https://grantseltzer.github.io/blog/dissecting-go-binaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 03:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantseltzer.github.io/blog/dissecting-go-binaries/</guid>
      <description>This post will introduce you to the basic concepts of disassembly and walk through writing a simple disassembler in Go. The goal is to make the whole concept of disassembly as accessible as possible and hopefully give you, the reader, a takeaway or two about how compiled Go binaries work. 
Assembly code cannot lie. By reading assembly we become as close as possible to knowing what’s being run on our computer chips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://grantseltzer.github.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grantseltzer.github.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a software engineer working for Capsule8 in Brooklyn, New York. My interests include systems programming, video games, hiking, watching baseball, and reading. I mostly will be writing about systems programming and sabermetrics, thank you for reading!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of me:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>